Okay, hello folks.
大家好
So as Justin just said, sorry for the folks on the recording for whom I forgot to start.
就像Justin刚才说的 对于录音中我忘记开始的人 很抱歉
We're going to talk about testing.
我们要谈论一下测试
So let's do that.
那我们就开始吧
So.
嗯
So far in CS61A and CS88 and other classes that you've taken, when you wrote code, how did you know that the code worked?
在CS61A、CS88和其他你参加过的课程中 当你写代码时 你是怎么知道代码是有效的呢
Well, probably how you knew that the code worked is somebody else gave you tests to check if your code worked.
你知道代码有效的方式可能是有人给你一些测试 来检查你的代码是否有效
So on Project Zero, we gave you tests to check if your code works.
在 Project Zero 上 我们给你一些测试来检查你的代码是否有效
In 61A, they gave you a bunch of tests.
在 61A 中 他们给了你一堆测试
There was this magical autograder that would tell you if you got the points or not, and that would tell you if your code is correct or not.
有这个神奇的自动评分器 会告诉你是否得分 以及告诉你你的代码是否正确
So today, it's kind of a philosophical lecture.
今天 这有点像一堂哲学讲座
There's not a lot of syntax to memorize or new concepts.
没有很多语法需要记忆或新概念
But the idea today is to give you the power to figure out whether your code works yourselves without having to rely on us writing an autograder for you.
但今天的想法是给你力量 让你能够自己判断你的代码是否有效 而不必依赖我们给你写一个自动评分器
Because if you go in the real world, industry, research, there are no autograders out there.
因为在现实世界中 工业、研究中 是没有自动评分器的
So we have to learn how to do it.
所以我们必须学会如何做
write tests and check that our code works without autograders.
编写测试并检查我们的代码是否可以在没有自动评分器的情况下正常工作
I will say up front that it's usually very hard, if not impossible, to check if your code is 100% completely correct.
我会提前说 通常情况下 要检查代码是否完全正确是非常困难的 甚至是不可能的
There are very rare cases where that's possible.
很少有情况是可能的
You can write little mathematical proofs to check if your code is correct, but that's kind of an edge case.
您可以编写一些小的数学证明来检查您的代码是否正确 但那算是个例外情况
Most people don't do that.
大多数人不这样做
So even though we can't be completely sure that our code is 100% correct, we can write ourselves some tests that'll give us very strong evidence that it's correct.
即使我们不能完全确定我们的代码是100%正确的 我们可以编写一些测试来为我们提供非常强有力的证据表明它是正确的
So that's the philosophy we're going to try to do today.
所以今天我们要尝试做的就是这个哲学
We're going to try to give you the skills to go out in your first project and in the world and code things using this new way.
我们要尝试给你们技能 让你们能够在你们的第一个项目和世界中使用这种新方法编码
So I'm not going to play the movie for time.
我不会放电影来浪费时间
But Josh has this movie that he likes to show.
但Josh有他喜欢播放的电影
It's like a little training montage.
就像是一个小训练蒙太奇
So yeah, we'll play it.
是的 我们会放的
OK.
好的
So see, that's you, right?
你看 那就是你 对吧
You're the one in the back.
你就是后面那个
And you're learning how to write tests for the first time.
而且你是第一次学着写测试
And this is us.
这就是我们
We're doing the training montage for you.
我们正在为你做训练集锦
You can't do this yet, but by the end of today, you will be able to.
你现在还做不到这一点 但今天结束时 你就能做到了
That's you, just getting the hang of it.
那就是你 慢慢就能掌握了
OK, so you get the idea.
你明白了
OK, so to figure out how to write tests and how to debug our programs by ourselves without the help of the magical autograder to help, we're going to need an example.
为了弄清楚如何编写测试以及如何自己调试程序 而不依赖神奇的自动评分程序的帮助 我们需要一个例子
So in past semesters, Josh would use sorting as an example.
过去的学期 Josh 会以排序作为例子
This semester, tell us what we're doing.
这学期 告诉我们我们在做什么
What have you subjected me to?
你让我经历了什么
Here you go.
给你
All right.
好的
So this semester, we're going to try something new.
这个学期 我们要尝试一些新东西
All right?
好吗
So I have written some code, and I've written a problem.
我写了一些代码 还有一个问题
Parin, you are not aware of it at this time.
帕林 你现在还不知道它
I've never seen it before.
我以前从未见过它
So I have written a problem, and I've written some buggy code.
我写了一个问题 还写了一些有错误的代码
And Parin is going to use your help to debug the code.
帕林会用你的帮助来调试代码的
You ready?
你准备好了吗
Let's do this.
咱们开始吧
OK, so should I look at the prompt now?
那我现在应该看提示吗
Should we look at the prompt together?
我们一起看提示吗
Yes.
是的
Look at the prompt and go.
看提示然后开始
So usually when I'm up here, I will sometimes lie to you and say, oh, we're trying this for the first time, but I've done it like five times before.
通常我在这里的时候 有时会骗你说 我们是第一次尝试这个 但我之前已经做过五次了
I am not lying.
我没在说谎
I have never actually seen this before.
我之前从来没真正见过这个
So let's read it together.
我们一起来读一下吧
I legitimately need like one minute to read this.
我确实需要大概一分钟来读这个
So you can take one minute to read it as well.
那么你也可以花一分钟来看看
There's a link in the very first slide.
在第一张幻灯片里有个链接
The reason why it's not on the slides is because I was not allowed to look at it.
它没在幻灯片上是因为我不允许看它
So it couldn't be on the slides.
不能放在幻灯片上
OK, I'll read it.
我会读给你听
You can read it with me.
你可以和我一起读
So we're going to read.
那我们就开始读吧
I need to compute the variance.
我需要计算方差
So I need to compute the average.
我需要计算平均值
OK, fair enough.
够公平
And then for each one, item x, I compute x minus the average.
然后对于每一个 项目 x 我计算 x 减去平均值
And I square the number.
然后我对这个数字求平方
And then I take the average of all the squared differences.
然后我取所有平方差的平均值
And thankfully, I've been given an example, which is nice.
幸运的是 我得到了一个例子 这很好
So 1, 2, 3, 4.
1、2、3、4
The mean is 2.5.
平均值是 2.5
For each number, I subtract 2.5.
对于每个数字 我减去了 2.5
I square it.
我把它平方了
I get these four numbers.
我得到这四个数字
And I average those.
然后我取平均值
And I get 1.25.
我得到了1.25
This, I'm not calculating that, but I'll take your word that that's the right answer.
这个 我不是在计算那个 但我相信你说的是正确的答案
So this is the function we have to write.
这就是我们要写的函数
Are people good with this?
大家对这个满意吗
Do you need more time to read this?
你需要更多时间来阅读这个吗
I feel like I sort of got it.
我觉得我有点明白了
OK.
好的
All right, if you need more time, the PDF is still there.
如果你需要更多时间 PDF 还在那里
The link is there.
链接在那里
OK.
好的
So we're not doing SORT anymore.
我们不再做 SORT 了
We're going to try this new variance thing for the first time ever.
我们将首次尝试这个新的变量的东西
So philosophically, what would we do if this were 61A or CS88?
从哲学的角度来看 如果这是61A或CS88 我们会怎么做
What we would do is we would immediately start writing our variance function.
我们会立即开始编写我们的方差函数
So pretend this is variance.
假装这是方差
And we would shove it into the magic autograder.
然后我们会把它塞进魔术自动评分器里
And the autograder would give us this beautiful output that tells us exactly what's wrong with our method and how to fix it.
评分器会给我们一个漂亮的输出 告诉我们方法有什么问题以及如何修复它
But in the real world, this thing doesn't exist.
但在现实世界中 这种东西是不存在的
So we're going to have to write our own tests to check that our variance function, so pretend this doesn't say sort.
我们得自己写测试来检查我们的方差函数 假装这里没有说排序
If you want to see the sort version, Josh has a video, but I'm not going to show it today.
如果你想看排序版本 Josh 有个视频 但今天我不会展示
So if you're curious, you can check it out.
如果你好奇的话 你可以去看一下
But today, we're going to write our own test variance test to check if our code works.
但今天 我们要写我们自己的测试方差函数 来检查我们的代码是否工作
OK, so how do we write tests?
好 那我们怎么写测试呢
I'll show you a couple more slides, and then we'll do it from scratch.
我会给你展示几张幻灯片 然后我们会从头开始做
So one way we could write it, and I'll just blaze through this because this is not what we usually do, is we could start by saying, this is what our input is.
我们可以写的一种方式 我会快速跑一遍因为这不是我们通常做的 是我们可以从说明我们的输入开始
This is what I wish the output was.
这是我希望的输出结果
So if I was hypothetically sorting, which I would have done in a happier time, then we would take this thing.
如果我假设排序的话 这是我在更快乐的时候可能会做的事情 那么我们就会拿这个东西
We'd sort it.
我们会对它进行排序
This would be the expected output.
这将是预期的输出
And then I'd have to somehow compare if the expected output is the same as what I'm what I get when I call sort.
然后我必须以某种方式比较预期输出和我调用排序时得到的结果是否相同
So I have to write some ridiculous code, like, well, maybe I'll write a for loop, and I'll check, are these two arrays equal?
我得写一些荒谬的代码 比如 也许我会写一个 for 循环 然后检查 这两个数组是否相等
And if they're not equal, I have to write my own little error message.
如果它们不相等 我就得写自己的小错误消息
So don't look at this too hard.
不要盯着它看太久
Don't stare at it too hard, because this is annoying.
不要盯着它看太久 因为这很烦人
It's tedious to write.
写起来很乏味
And if testing was like this, you would never do it, because it's not fun.
如果测试都像这样 你肯定不会做 因为这不好玩
You have to write these specific test error messages.
你得写这些具体的测试错误消息
You have to write this for loop.
你得写这个 for 循环
This is not fun.
这不好玩
I don't want to do this.
我不想做这个
So luckily, we don't have to do this, because this kind of code appears in basically every test ever we have to write.
幸运的是 我们不必这样做 因为这种代码基本上出现在我们必须编写的每个测试中
We have to check if the expected output is the same as the output that we get from calling our function.
我们必须检查预期输出是否与调用我们的函数后获得的输出相同
And I don't want to write this over and over again with the exact same error messages.
而且我不想一遍又一遍地写下完全相同的错误消息
That's too tedious.
那太繁琐了
So luckily, instead of writing tests like that, because that's no fun and no one would ever do that, we can use libraries that other people have written
幸运的是 我们不必像那样编写测试 因为那样既不好玩 也没有人会这样做 我们可以使用其他人编写的库
So other people wrote the unit testing libraries.
其他人写了单元测试库
They did all the hard work of coming up with the complicated error messages and the checks and the looping through of arrays.
他们做了所有繁重的工作 包括制定复杂的错误消息、检查和遍历数组
So instead of doing all that ourselves, we're just going to make someone else do it.
我们不会自己做所有这些 我们只是让别人来做
And there are a bunch of different libraries out there for this.
而且 有很多不同的库可供选择
The one that we're going to use is called Truth, which was developed by Google.
我们要使用的一个叫做Truth 是由Google开发的
So we're going to use that.
我们会用它
Maybe in past semesters, people used different ones.
也许在过去的学期里 人们使用了不同的库
We're not going to do sorting anymore, unfortunately.
我们不会再做排序了 不幸的是
But we'll jump into this code, which I have literally never seen before, and we'll see what's going on.
但我们将深入研究这段代码 这是我从未见过的 我们将看看发生了什么
So I'm not going to open the correct one.
我不会打开正确的那个
I'm going to open the testing file.
我要打开测试文件
OK, I guess I'll also mention briefly, as you can see, this lecture is going to be completely chaotic and disorganized, because I have no idea what's going on.
我想我还会简要提一下 正如你们所看到的 这节课将完全混乱和无组织 因为我不知道发生了什么
But maybe we'll figure it out together.
但也许我们可以一起弄清楚
So one thing I will note at some point, I guess right now, is that not this, not this.
有一件事我会在某个时候注意到 我想现在就是时候了 就是不是这个 不是这个
OK, maybe not.
好吧 或许不是
A little slide for it?
给它滑个小动作
OK, that's fine. Like I said, we're weeing it.
没问题  就像我说的 我们正在看它
We're live.
我们正在直播
OK, so instead of writing tests after we write our function, so normally what you might expect you to do is you'd write the function.
我们不是在写完函数后再写测试 通常你可能期望的是你会先写函数
And you're like, this thing totally worked.
然后你就会觉得 这东西完全可行
And then you'll write your test and see if they work.
然后你会写你的测试看看它们是否起作用
But a very strange idea, which we'll talk about maybe at the end if we have time
and if I get through this whole ordeal, is instead of checking after we write our code whether it works, I want to do something a little bit strange,
which is I'm actually going to check if the code works and write my tests before I even write the code.
但有个非常奇怪的想法 可能在最后我们有时间的话会谈论一下
如果我能通过这整个磨难的话 就是在我们写代码后而不是之后检查它是否有效 我想做一些有点奇怪的事情
那就是我实际上要检查代码是否有效 并在甚至编写代码之前就编写我的测试
Whoa, mind blown what's going on.
哇 脑洞大开 发生了什么
So the idea here is that before we even write the code, and the code is there, we haven't written it yet, we're actually going to start by writing the tests.
这里的想法是 在我们甚至编写代码之前 代码就在那里 我们还没有写它 我们实际上要开始编写测试
And then after we have our tests, then we're going to go and write our code.
然后在我们有了测试之后 我们就会去编写我们的代码
It's kind of a weird backwards idea, but we're going to try it.
这有点奇怪的倒行逆施的想法 但我们要试试看
OK, so. I wish I had a slide for that.
所以 我希望我有个幻灯片
I swear I did.
我发誓我做了
Maybe it's this one.
也许是这个
OK, so kind of. You can read this if you're interested.
有点像  如果你感兴趣 你可以读这个
Basically, the idea is we're going to write the test first.
基本上 我们的想法是先写测试
The test is going to fail because we haven't written the code yet.
测试会失败 因为我们还没写代码
Then we're going to try to write the code to make the test pass.
然后我们要尝试编写代码 使测试通过
OK, that's the idea.
那就是想法
So how do we write tests?
那么我们如何编写测试呢
Well, first I should figure out what the function is.
首先我应该弄清楚这个函数是什么
Am I allowed to open this file, variants?
我可以打开这个文件吗 变体
OK, because the main thing I want to figure out is what the signature is.
因为我想弄清楚的主要是签名是什么
This is the only one.
这是唯一的一个
Yes, I'll zoom in.
好的 我会放大
What do you want me to zoom in on?
你想让我放大什么
The PDF.
PDF 文件
The PDF, OK.
PDF 文件 好的
So I guess, first off, how are you planning on solving this?
我猜 首先 你打算如何解决这个问题
So you want me to talk about my coding approach or my testing approach?
你是想让我谈谈我的编码方法还是测试方法
Your coding approach.
你的编码方法
My coding approach, OK.
我的编码方法 好的
Well, it seems like there's a function for me to write here, which is public static double variance, takes in the array.
看起来这里有一个函数需要我写 它是public static double variance 接收一个数组
I mean, I guess I'd write a helper function, because I don't want to do everything in one method.
我的意思是 我想我会写一个辅助函数 因为我不想把所有事情都放在一个方法里面
So I'd probably write a method that computes the average, maybe.
我可能会写一个计算平均值的方法 也许
Because you gave me three steps.
因为你给了我三个步骤
I guess I'll write a helper method for the first one.
我想我会为第一个写一个辅助方法
Maybe I'd put this in a helper method, like subtract the mean and square it.
也许我会把这个放在一个辅助方法里 像是减去平均值然后平方
Maybe that goes in a helper method.
也许那应该放在一个辅助方法中
And then I guess I could use the average method again on my third step.
然后我想我可以在我的第三步再次使用平均方法
You're looking at me funny, like what's going on?
你用奇怪的眼神看着我 像在想什么
OK.
好的
I'm not looking at you funny.
我没用奇怪的眼神看着你
I'm looking at you.
我是在看着你
OK, well, that's, I think, what I would do.
我想 那就是我会做的
So anyway, given that there's a variance function, I guess I'm going to try writing some tests.
总之 既然有一个方差函数 我想我要尝试写一些测试
So what test should I write?
那么我应该写什么测试呢
Well, I was going to write the one in the example that you gave to me, but it seems like you've already written that.
我本来打算写你给我的那个例子中的测试 但看起来你已经写过了
So maybe I'll just pretend you didn't write it, and I'll write it.
也许我会假装你没写过 然后我自己写一个
OK, we'll make new ones.
我们会新建一些
OK, so there's a little bit of syntax here.
这里有一点语法
I don't care if you memorize it, because frankly, it's just not very interesting.
我不在乎你是否记住它 因为说实话 它并不是很有趣
So I'll show you the syntax a little bit, but it's not that interesting.
那么我会给你展示一下语法 但这并不是很有趣
So I'll write public void, and then I'll write the name of the test.
那么我会写public void 然后我会写测试的名称
So I don't know, test, variance, lecture.
那么我不知道 测试 方差 讲座
OK, great.
好的 太棒了
So let's write a test.
那么让我们写一个测试吧
So what should our input array be?
那么我们的输入数组应该是什么呢
I don't know.
我不知道
Don't look at me.
别看我
I don't know the answers.
我不知道答案
Don't we already have 1, 2, 3, 4?
我们不是已经有1、2、3、4了吗
That's what I was trying to use earlier. 10, 20, 30, 40.
这就是我之前试图使用的  10、20、30、40
Sure.
当然
OK.
好的
10, 20, 30, 40.
10 20 30 40
OK.
好
Great.
很好
So usually, when we write a test, what we do is we'll do two things.
通常 当我们编写测试时 我们会做两件事
So first, we're going to think ourselves, without looking at the code, what would a correct answer be?
首先 我们会自己思考一下 在不看代码的情况下 正确答案会是什么
And then we'll call the method that we're going to write, and then see if our method gives the correct answer.
然后我们会调用我们要编写的方法 然后看看我们的方法是否给出了正确答案
So I'll write expected, and I'll write actual, and we'll see if they match.
我会写期望的值 然后写实际的值 然后我们会看它们是否匹配
So the answer should be a double, right?
答案应该是一个双精度浮点数 对吧
OK.
好的
So what is the expected answer here?
那么这里期望的答案是什么
I have no idea.
我不知道
OK.
好的
Is it actually 125?
实际上是125吗
Are you being real, or is this like we're going to put in some extra bugs to make life even harder?
你是认真的 还是像我们之前说的要加一些额外的 bug 来让生活变得更难
OK, I'll take your word for it.
我会相信你的
So if I did not have Justin here, what I would have done is I probably would have gone into Google and done the math myself, and I would have gotten
如果我没有贾斯汀在这里 我可能会去谷歌自己算一下 然后得出结果
Probably 125.
大概是125
OK, great.
好的 太棒了
That's what the expected value is.
那就是预期值
So what's the actual value?
那么实际值是多少呢
Well, the actual value is what would happen if I called the actual method.
实际值是如果我调用实际方法会发生的事情
This is why I want to know what the method actually looks like.
这就是我想知道方法实际上是什么样子的原因
So I'll just take a guess.
我就随便猜一下
I'm guessing it's in the variance class.
我猜它在方差类里面
Not the correct one.
不是正确的那一个
I'm guessing it's the variance function.
我猜它是方差函数
And I guess I pass it an input.
我猜我把一个输入传递给它
OK.
好的
So normally, you'd be able to open this file and see what the method signature is.
通常 你应该能打开这个文件并查看方法签名
But I guess I'm not allowed to, so I won't.
但我想我不能 我不会
OK, great.
好的 太好了
And then finally, I should check if the value is equal.
最后 我应该检查值是否相等
So this is the part where we're going to use the truth library.
这就是我们将要使用 truth 库的部分
So it's already been helpfully imported for me.
这个库已经帮我导入了
I don't really care about the import statements.
我不太在乎导入语句
You can just leave them up there.
你可以就让它们留在那儿
So I'll write something like assert that.
那我会写一些像是 'assert that' 这样的东西
And the nice thing about Google Truth, I guess I'll briefly mention, is that it kind of reads like English.
关于Google Truth的好处 我想我会简要提一下 它有点像阅读英语
So it's almost like I'm writing an English sentence, which is kind of nice.
写起来几乎就像是写英语句子一样 挺好的
So even if you don't remember the exact syntax, sometimes you can just guess your way through it, which is what I often do.
即使你记不住确切的语法 有时你也可以猜一下 这是我经常做的事情
So I kind of want to check if actual and expected are the same.
我想检查一下实际值和预期值是否相同
So maybe I'll just say assert that actual is equal to expected.
也许我就说实际值等于预期值
That's really nice because now I don't have to manually write my own error message.
这真的很好 因为现在我不必手动编写自己的错误消息了
I don't have to manually check if they're equal.
我不必手动检查它们是否相等
So this statement will check if they're equal for me and also helpfully print out an error message if it's wrong, which is kind of nice.
这个语句会帮我检查它们是否相等 如果不相等还会友好地打印出一个错误消息 这感觉挺不错的
Okay, one little problem is it seems like all the other tests that were written, they have these little run buttons so I can run the tests.
好吧 有一个小问题 似乎所有其他编写的测试都有这些小运行按钮 我可以运行测试
like you were doing in project zero.
就像你在项目零中所做的那样
There's no run button here, so what do I do?
这里没有运行按钮 那我该怎么办呢
So one possible idea is I could write a main method, and then in my main method, I could call my test variants.
一个可能的想法是我可以写一个主方法 然后在我的主方法中 我可以调用我的测试变体
But that's a little annoying, and it's not what you did in the project.
但这有点烦人 而且这不是你在项目中所做的
So instead, I'm not going to describe how it's done or how this works under the hood.
我不打算描述它是如何完成的或者它是如何在底层工作的
You can check out the extra videos if you're curious.
如果你好奇的话 你可以看看额外的视频
But I'm going to add this funny new syntax, which is just at test.
但我会添加这个有趣的新语法 这只是一个测试
I think that's the one I want.
我觉得这就是我想要的
OK, maybe not.
好吧 也许不是
At test.
一个测试
Does it work?
它能工作吗
OK, great.
好的 太棒了
And so what this will do is somehow, for reasons that I haven't explained, it will magically put a run symbol here.
这将以某种方式做的是 出于我尚未解释的原因 它会神奇地在这里放置一个运行符号
And that's going to let me run this test.
这将让我运行这个测试
How does that work?
那是怎么做到的
Not terribly important right now.
现在不是非常重要
But if you put in the magic words, you'll have this nice little test that you can run.
但如果你输入了魔法词 你会有一个可以运行的小测试
OK, should we write more tests to be confident?
我们应该写更多的测试来增加信心吗
Maybe we should.
或许我们应该
Maybe we shouldn't.
或许我们不应该
Does anyone have questions about what we're doing, about why we're doing this?
有人对我们正在做的事情 以及为什么要这样做有疑问吗
Yeah.
是的
Yeah, that's a great question.
是的 这是个很好的问题
It's not one I don't have the answer to because I've never seen this code.
这不是我没有答案的问题 因为我从未见过这段代码
OK, there was a question about what if the numbers are just slightly off by 0.0001.
关于如果数字只是稍微差了0.0001 有一个问题
Apparently, Google's truth has some syntax.
显然 Google的真相有一些语法
I'm not going to read that.
我不打算读那个
But I guess you can do assert that output is within a little bit of off by some range of this big number.
但我猜你可以断言输出在这个大数的一点点范围内
OK, sounds good. Exciting.
听起来不错  令人兴奋
So yeah, Google Druid has lots of different features.
是的 Google Druid有很多不同的功能
You're not going to use all of them.
你不会用到它们全部
Just a small subset.
只用其中一小部分
For today, it seems like is equal to will do most of the job for us.
就今天而言 似乎 is equal to 就能完成大部分工作了
Should we write more tests?
我们是不是应该写更多的测试
Should we launch into the debugging?
是不是应该开始调试了
Edge cases, that's a good point.
边界情况 这是个好点子
So maybe sometimes when we write functions, some of the inputs are weird.
有时候当我们写函数时 一些输入是奇怪的
So maybe this is like a normal-ish input.
也许这就像一个正常的输入
Are there any weird inputs that we have to deal with, perhaps, that we should think about?
有没有我们需要考虑的奇怪输入 也许 我们应该考虑一下
Sorry, say it one more time.
抱歉 再说一遍
I have no idea who said what.
我不知道谁说了什么
Empty list, OK, sure, let's do that.
空列表 好的 确保 我们来做吧
So maybe I'll give this a more descriptive name this time.
也许这次我会给这个一个更具描述性的名字
So test empty list.
那么测试空列表
So I think that's valid syntax.
我觉得那是有效的语法
Empty list, OK.
空列表 好的
So the expected value, what is the expected behavior?
那么预期值 预期行为是什么
I don't know. I'll check my spec.
我不知道  我会检查我的规范
Does the spec tell me what to do if I get an empty list?
规范告诉我如果我得到一个空列表该怎么办吗
Hello?
喂
你好
At the very bottom.
就在最底下
Ah, it does.
啊 是的
OK, so I just can't read.
我就是看不懂
So it returns the variance of that list for 0 if the array has length 0.
它返回该列表的方差 如果数组的长度为0 则返回0
Aha.
啊哈
So that tells me that the expected should be 0.
这告诉我预期应该是0
That tells me that what's the actual?
这告诉我实际是什么
The actual would be what happens if I actually call the variance function.
实际将是如果我实际调用方差函数会发生什么
OK.
好的
And I can just do the same assert statement as before.
我可以像以前一样做相同的断言语句
OK.
好的
Is equal to?
等于
OK, expected.
符合预期
Great.
太好了
Any other weird edge cases I should deal with before I?
在我开始之前 还有其他奇怪的边界情况需要处理吗
The numbers are repeated.
这些数字重复了
I like that one.
我喜欢那个
Let's do that.
就这样吧
OK.
好的
What number should I use?
我应该使用什么数字
As you can see, I'm totally winging this.
你看 我完全是临时起意的
I have no idea what's going on.
我不知道发生了什么
OK.
好的
What number should I use?
我应该使用什么数字
Perhaps I'll just copy-paste because I'm lazy.
也许我就直接复制粘贴吧 因为我有点懒
61.
OK.
好的
Is that good?
这样好吗
What's the variance?
方差是多少
I think it's 0.
我觉得是0
OK, great.
好的 太棒了
And if I wasn't sure, what would I do?
如果我不确定怎么办
I'd just go into a calculator and do all this math, which I'm not going to do.
我只需要打开计算器 做所有这些数学运算 但我现在不想这么做
But apparently it's 0.
但显然是0
Anything else you want to try?
还有其他你想尝试的吗
Negative numbers.
负数
You're really testing me now.
你现在真的在考验我了
OK, so you're testing the function, which is good.
你在测试这个函数 这很好
OK, let's do test negative.
让我们测试负数
What negative numbers should we use?
我们应该使用哪些负数
Don't look at me.
别看我
I don't have the answers.
我没有答案
Negative 8, OK.
负八 好的
There's a plot twist at the end.
结局有个反转
OK.
好的
Aha, you're on the spot now.
啊哈 你现在难办了
Not me anymore.
不是我了
Let's calculate.
我们来算一下
Quickly, quickly, or else I'm going to beat you.
快点 快点 不然我要打你了
Negative 1, negative 2.
负一 负二
Should I click it?
我应该点击吗
I don't know what sample and population are.
我不知道样本和总体是什么
I don't remember any of this stuff.
我一个也不记得了
Is that minus 1?
那是负一吗
That's not what I want. That's not.
这不是我想要的  不是这样的
Aw.
啊
29 over 4, I think.
我想是 29 除以 4
29 over 4.
29 除以 4
Look at that.
看那个
OK.
好的
7.25?
Ooh.
哦
OK.
好的
7.25.
7.25
I didn't do the math.
我没算过
I'm just looking at it.
我只是在看它
I didn't do the math.
我没算过
You cheated.
你作弊了
OK. I was still starting with the first two numbers.
好的  我还是从前两个数字开始
You cheated.
你作弊了
OK.
好的
That's fine.
没关系
I cheated, too.
我也作弊了
OK.
好的
I could even set my sources if I wanted to.
如果我愿意 我甚至可以设置我的源代码
OK.
好的
Anything else?
还有其他事吗
Yeah, anything else?
是的 还有其他事吗
Just in case.
以防万一
I'll do one more.
我再做一个
Yeah, that's a good point.
是的 那是个很好的观点
I didn't know that you had an average method, so I didn't test it.
我不知道你有一个平均方法 我没有测试过
But if you have an average method, then I'll certainly try and test it.
但如果你有一个平均方法 那么我肯定会尝试并测试它
So what should I test average with?
那么我应该用什么来测试平均值
I see.
我明白了
You gave me the hint.
你给了我一个提示
OK, so what should I test average with?
那我应该用什么来测试平均值
Any edge cases, thoughts?
有什么边界情况 想法吗
0?
Sure.
当然
So same thing I'll do.
那我就做同样的事情
And yeah, I guess it's a little bit tedious sometimes, but that's kind of how testing goes.
是的 我想有时候可能有点乏味 但这就是测试的方式
So just zero by itself.
就只是零本身
I want to confirm that's what you want.
我想确认这就是你想要的
OK.
好的
Expected equals zero, because the average of zero is zero.
预期等于零 因为零的平均值是零
OK.
好的
OK, average.
平均值
You'll still get the right answer.
你仍然会得到正确的答案
I will still get the right answer, you're sure.
我仍然会得到正确的答案 你确定吗
OK.
好的
And I'll just copy this little equal of actual unexpected.
而且我只会复制这个实际意外的小等式
OK.
好的
I'll write maybe like two more, and then we should get going, because I don't know how long this debugging is going to take me.
我再写两个 然后我们就可以开始了 因为我不知道调试要花多长时间
What else do you want?
你还想要什么
Empty.
空的
Empty, OK.
空的 好的
I have no clue what the average method is supposed to do when it's empty, though.
我完全不知道平均方法在空时应该做什么 不过
What do you want it to do?
你希望它做什么
I don't know.
我不知道
You wrote the method.
你写了这个方法
OK.
好的
Sure, I'm going to pretend it's going to return.
好吧 我会假装它会返回
Should it return zero?
它应该返回零吗
I don't know.
我不知道
I guess I'll have it return zero, because I feel like it.
我猜我会让它返回零 因为我觉得这样做
We'll see what happens.
我们会看看会发生什么
OK, anything else?
还有其他事吗
No more?
没有了吗
One more?
还有吗
Should we just write like a, what did you want?
我们应该写像是 你想要什么
Oh, yeah, repeat it, sure.
是的 重复一下 当然
What should we do?
我们该怎么办
Like that?
就这样
OK, I hope the average.
我希望平均一点
You want to make it hard?
你想搞得难一点吗
OK, what should I add?
我应该加什么
Go!
开始！
Calculate!
算一下！
What number do you want?
你想要什么数字
Okay, how's that?
这样可以吗
Okay.
好的
That's more doable?
这样更容易做到了吗
You want me to change it?
你要我改变吗
I'll change it.
我会改的
23?
Okay, if you say so, boss.
如果你这么说 老板
Seven?
Oh, okay, because it's clean.
好的 因为它很干净
All right, sure.
当然
Okay, I like it.
我喜欢它
OK, should we check that some of the doubles, because all the doubles we've checked that are all 0.0?
我们应该检查一下一些双倍 因为我们检查过的所有双倍都是 0.0
Maybe we should check one that's not 0.0?
也许我们应该检查一个不是 0.0 的
Yeah, all of these are integers.
是的 所有这些都是整数
OK, because maybe there's some little error with integers and not integers that you snuck in there to get me.
因为也许有一些关于整数和非整数的小错误是你偷偷放进去的 想要骗我
But I see your game.
但我看穿你的把戏了
I'm not going to let you check that.
我不会让你检查那个的
So I'm not going to let you get away with that.
我不会让你得逞
So what if this was 24?
那么如果这是 24 呢
And this would no longer be 7.0, right?
这样就不再是7.0了 对吧
4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9.
4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9
Oh, that's too many.
那太多了
OK, what about like that?
那像这样呢
Now it's like 7.0.
现在就像是7.0了
1, 2, 5?
1, 2, 5
2, 5?
2, 5
35, 24, 59, 59 over 8.
35, 24, 59, 59 分之 8
So it's 1, 2, 5?
所以是 1、2、5
7, 3, 7, 5?
7、3、7、5
3, 7, 5.
3、7、5
OK, sure.
好的 当然
I think.
我觉得
What do you mean you think?
你说的是什么意思
OK, I'll check.
我会检查
I do mental math.
我做心算
I'm guessing there's a 50% chance I'm right.
我猜有50%的几率我是对的
That is true.
那是真的
All right, let's find out.
让我们找出来
It's 375.
是375
OK, great.
太棒了
So this will also test that not all of my numbers are ending in 0.
这也将测试到 我的数字并不是全部都以0结尾
So again, this is not really like a science.
再说一遍 这实际上不像是一门科学
There's no right answer.
没有正确答案
It's more like an art.
更像是一门艺术
So we had to go through and think about edge cases ourselves.
我们不得不自己去考虑边界情况
You thought of some great ones, like empty and repeated.
你想到了一些很棒的情况 比如空的和重复的
I thought of one, which was these all end in 0.0.
我想到了一个 就是这些都以0.0结尾
What if they don't end in 0.0?
如果它们不是以0.0结尾会怎样
And sometimes coming up with these is a little tricky.
有时候想出这些有点棘手
But it seems like we have something going.
但似乎我们有点头绪了
Are we good to start?
我们可以开始了吗
There is one other edge case I would personally do.
我还有一个我个人会处理的边缘情况
Yeah, what do you want to do?
是的 你想做什么
That's a good point.
这是个好观点
So in the same way that I just came up with one where it doesn't end in 0.0, what if the inputs don't end in 0.0?
就像我刚刚想到的一个不以0.0结尾的一样 如果输入不以0.0结尾呢
That's a good one.
这个不错
We should do that.
我们应该这样做
So let's do it for both average and maybe also variance.
那么我们就来计算平均值 可能还有方差吧
Well, this will be some fun math.
这将是一些有趣的数学
So you want the input to not be integers.
你希望输入不是整数
So maybe we do 5.5 and 6.5.
也许我们可以用5.5和6.5试试
Not too complicated.
不太复杂
I would hope the average of that is 6.
我希望平均值是6
Great.
太好了
Maybe let's do one for variance, too.
也许我们也可以做一个方差的
OK, so what should I do?
那我该怎么做呢
Test, average, repeated.
测试、平均值、重复
OK, I guess I'll borrow this one.
我想我会借用这个
Actually, 1.5, 2.5, 3.5, 1.5.
实际上 1.5、2.5、3.5、1.5
You want 1.5, 2.5, 3.5?
你想要1.5、2.5、3.5吗
OK, sure, let's do that.
当然 让我们这样做
I don't want to do the math part.
我不想做数学那部分
Sure.
当然
OK, so what's the variance of this one?
那这个的方差是多少
1.25.
1.25
1.25?
All right, if you say so.
如果你这么说的话
OK, cool.
好的 很酷
So now we have a little bit of extra checks.
现在我们多了一点额外的检查
Variance, OK.
方差 好的
OK.
好的
True.
OK.
好的
OK, looks good.
看起来不错
So we wrote a bunch of tests.
我们写了一堆测试
And crucially, we did so before we even wrote any line of code.
而且至关重要的是 我们在编写任何代码之前就已经这样做了
And so that's the key idea.
这就是关键的想法
You don't have to use this idea, but I find it really nice, because it means before you even start writing the code,
你不一定要使用这个想法 但我觉得这个想法真的很好 因为这意味着在你开始编写代码之前
you've already gone through all the thinking of like, oh, you've got to be really careful, because these might not be integers.
你已经经历了所有思考 比如 你必须非常小心 因为这些可能不是整数
And be really careful, because these aren't integers.
要非常小心 因为这些不是整数
And oh, by writing these tests, I also kind of realized, hey, maybe I need an average method.
通过编写这些测试 我也有点意识到 也许我需要一个平均方法
So somehow, by writing these tests before even jumping into the code, I got a better idea of how to write my code.
以某种方式 在甚至跳入代码之前编写这些测试 我对如何编写我的代码有了更好的了解
That's kind of cool.
这有点酷
OK, so I believe now's the moment of truth, and we should run all these tests with the code that we haven't written yet and see if it works.
我相信现在是真相的时刻 我们应该运行所有这些测试 用我们还没有编写的代码 看看是否有效
Yes, I can click this?
是的 我可以点击这个吗
It's going to explode.
它会爆炸的
OK, that's fine.
没问题
But the idea is that technically, the code is blank.
但是问题是 从技术上讲 代码是空白的
We haven't done anything yet.
我们还什么都没做
You and I haven't done anything yet.
你和我什么都还没做
So we're going to run it.
我们要运行它
And unsurprisingly, most of the things we wrote didn't pass.
毫不奇怪 我们写的大部分东西都没有通过
Not too surprising.
也不算太奇怪
OK, so I also have a slide for this.
我也有一张关于这个的幻灯片
I just don't know where it is anymore.
我只是不知道它在哪里了
Here's my slide.
这是我的幻灯片
Here, this is the one I want to tell you about.
这里 这就是我想告诉你的那个
So we already saw the syntax to add the word add test that will somehow magically make the run button appear.
我们已经看到了添加单词 add test 的语法 这将以某种方式神奇地使运行按钮出现
More details in the bonus videos if you care.
如果你在意的话 在奖励视频中有更多细节
But one thing that I find really cool at this point is that now the
但在这一点上我发现真的很酷的一件事是现在
The process of debugging and making this broken code work, it kind of becomes like a game.
调试和使这段错误的代码工作的过程 有点像一个游戏
So as opposed to just you writing code with no goal, as humans, we like having goals to strive toward.
与仅仅编写没有目标的代码相反 作为人类 我们喜欢有目标可以努力实现
So something I find really nice about IntelliJ in particular is that now we have this list and see all these Xs, and I'm like, I don't want the Xs to go away.
我发现 IntelliJ 特别好的一点是现在我们有这个列表 可以看到所有这些 X 我不想让 X 消失
And as I change my code, I'm going to slowly make these Xs go away.
随着我改变我的代码 我会慢慢让这些 X 消失
And I know that if they all show up as checks, then I win.
我知道如果它们都显示为检查标记 那么我就赢了
And it might feel philosophically kind of like a small thing, but this is the kind of thing that we can use to, I don't know, motivate ourselves, give ourselves clear goals as to what to do next.
这在哲学上可能感觉有点微小 但这是我们可以用来激励自己的东西 给自己明确的下一步做什么的目标
Because sometimes figuring out what to do next is kind of hard.
因为有时候弄清楚下一步该做什么有点难
This is why people.
这就是人们为什么
Zoom chat found a bug in one of the tests.
Zoom聊天发现了一个测试中的一个错误
Go to test, I think, empty list.
去测试 我想 空列表
Empty list, yeah.
空列表 是的
This one?
这个吗
Yeah, or go to test average empty.
是的 或者去测试平均空
Test average empty.
测试平均空
Yeah, what about it?
是啊 有什么事吗
Never mind.
没事了
Wow.
哇
OK.
好的
Wow.
哇
Thanks a lot, Zoom.
非常感谢 Zoom
OK.
好的
They were saying that there was a variance on variance, but there should be a variance on average.
他们在说方差上有变化 但应该是平均数上有变化
Oh.
哦
Well, to be fair, I'm switching back and forth a lot, so I can't blame them.
公平地说 我经常来回切换 不能怪他们
I can't see that.
我看不到
I didn't see it there.
我没看到那里
That's all right.
没关系
OK.
好的
As I was saying, I find it really nice that now there's this little game you can play where there's a lot of x's, and you've got to make them all check marks, and you win.
就像我说的 我觉得现在有这样一个小游戏很不错 你可以玩 里面有很多x 你要把它们都变成勾号 然后你就赢了
Maybe that's why we're all so addicted to video games.
也许这就是为什么我们都对视频游戏这么上瘾吧
I don't know.
我不知道
What do the kids play these days?
现在的孩子们都玩些什么呢
I don't know.
我不知道
Genshin Impact.
原神
I don't know.
我不知道
I have no idea what that is, but people just tell me about it.
我不知道那是什么 但人们就是这么告诉我的
Yeah, so people are just like, oh, you attack the wizard and you get the magic coin or whatever.
是啊 就是人们说 你攻击那个巫师然后你就得到了魔法金币之类的
And this is kind of the same idea.
这个概念差不多
You attack all these little X's, you get the magic check marks.
你攻击所有这些小 X 你就得到了魔法勾选
OK, is it very obvious I have no idea how to play Genshin Impact?
好吧 我完全不会玩原神这个游戏 这很明显对吗
OK, excellent.
好的 太棒了
I have no idea what any of this stuff is out of my depth.
我完全不知道这些东西是什么 超出了我的理解范围
OK, so with the idea in mind that we want to make all these x's go away, it's time to actually run our tests.
想法是我们想让所有这些 x 消失 现在是时候实际运行我们的测试了
We already saw that they failed.
我们已经看到它们失败了
So now it's actually time to go in and write our methods.
现在是真正去编写我们的方法的时候了
So remember, the idea behind test-driven development, as people call it, is we write the tests first.
记住 测试驱动开发背后的想法 就像人们所说的那样 我们先写测试
As expected, they mostly fail.
正如预期的那样 它们大部分都失败了
Then we go into our method and write it armed with the extra knowledge that we have.
然后我们带着额外的知识进入我们的方法并编写它
So normally, I'd write it myself.
通常 我会自己写
But in the interest of keeping things chaotic...
但为了保持事情的混乱性……
Not really, but OK.
不是真的 但也行
So this is like one of those baking shows where you just watch them on TV, make food, and present it to you.
这就像那些烘焙节目 你只是在电视上看他们做食物 然后呈现给你
Like, they show, OK, you make the cake batter, and then you put it in the oven for three hours.
就像 他们展示 你做蛋糕糊 然后把它放进炉子烤三个小时
But we don't have three hours, so here's a new cake.
但我们没有三个小时 这里有一个新蛋糕
Oh, one of those.
就是那种
Yeah, yeah.
对 对
So on those cooking shows, they're like, we put it in the oven, and then we're like, that takes too long, so we'll just get the new cake out.
在那些烹饪节目里 他们会说 我们把它放进烤箱里 然后我们就会觉得 这太久了 我们就拿新蛋糕出来吧
OK.
好的
So this is the new code.
这是新代码
OK, so I've never seen this before.
我以前从未见过这个
I'm seeing it for the first time, as you are.
我和你一样 第一次见到它
So we'll inspect it.
我们会检查它
And immediately, we see tons of stuff failed.
立刻 我们看到有很多东西失败了
I will try my best to talk through it.
我会尽力讲清楚的
Sometimes I might just stare at it aimlessly if I'm truly stuck.
有时候 如果我真的卡住了 我可能会目不转睛地盯着它
But I will say, one strategy that I find kind of useful is I like solving these one by one.
但我想说的是 我发现一种策略挺有用的 就是我喜欢逐个解决这些问题
So sometimes it's tempting to be like, oh, there's so many x's.
有时候会很诱人 比如说 有这么多的 x
There's so many things I have to handle.
有这么多的事情我需要处理
So maybe instead of doing all of them at once, I'm going to pick one that I find pretty easy.
也许不是一次性全部做完 我会先挑一个我觉得比较简单的来做
I'll tackle the easy one first and hope that fixing the easy one causes all the harder ones to fix themselves.
我会先解决简单的问题 希望通过解决简单的问题 所有更难的问题都能迎刃而解
Is that actually going to happen?
这样真的会发生吗
I don't know, but it would certainly be nice if it did.
我不知道 但如果真的发生了那当然太好了
So let's go through.
那我们来逐个检查
Do any of the tests seem particularly easy that you'd like to take a shot at first?
有没有哪个测试看起来特别容易 你想先试试
Empty list seems pretty easy.
空列表看起来挺简单的
Let's do that.
我们来做吧
So what did empty list do?
那么空列表做了什么
It took in an empty list.
它接受了一个空列表
It wanted the output to be 0.
它希望输出为0
Let's go check.
我们去检查一下
So how should I do that?
那我该怎么做呢
Well, I could just stare at the code really hard and try to figure it out.
我可以盯着代码看看 努力试着弄清楚
But in the interest of actually trying to finish today, I'm going to use the debug feature, which we've seen before.
为了确实能在今天完成 我打算使用我们之前见过的调试功能
So I hit debug, nothing happened, still divided by zero error.
我点击了调试 但什么也没发生 仍然是除以零的错误
Why is that?
这是为什么呢
Well, first, it's because I haven't set a breakpoint yet, so I should probably do that.
首先 是因为我还没有设置断点 我应该先做这个
Maybe before even setting the breakpoint, I look at this and I'm like, wait a minute, the code crashed.
或许 在设置断点之前 我看了一眼代码 心里想 等等 代码崩溃了
And if the code crashed, it means I get a traceback.
如果代码崩溃了 意味着我会得到一个回溯
And what does the traceback tell me?
那么 回溯告诉我什么呢
It tells me where did the error happen.
它告诉我错误发生在哪里
It happened right here when I called variance.
当我调用方差时 它就发生在这里
And then this variance called line 13, which called average, and that called line 9.
然后这个方差调用了第13行 它调用了平均值 而那个调用了第9行
And here's where the crash is.
这就是崩溃的地方
So the traceback has already told me you're dividing by 0 right here.
回溯已经告诉我你正在这里除以0
That's kind of nice.
这还挺好的
So the traceback tells me something is wrong here.
回溯告诉我这里有问题
So I'm going to set a breakpoint right there, because the traceback is telling me your problem is right there.
我要在这里设置一个断点 因为回溯告诉我你的问题就在那里
Go check it out.
去看一下吧
OK, so let's do it.
那么让我们做吧
Let's debug.
让我们调试
And the program teleports here.
程序就会在这里传送
So what do I do in the debugger?
那么在调试器中我该怎么办呢
Again, it's more art than science.
再次强调 这更多是一门艺术而不是科学
I can look through the things that I'm passing in.
我可以浏览我传入的东西
And what do I notice?
我注意到了什么
I'm passing in an empty array, which kind of makes sense.
我传入了一个空数组 这有点说得通
That's what I passed in here.
这就是我传入的
It's empty.
它是空的
I can see, hmm, sum is 0.
我可以看到 总和是0
And then at this point, I'm trying to divide by nums.lame.
然后在这一点上 我试图除以nums.lame
Aha, that's 0.
这是 0 哈
So I think I'm going to fix this by adding a special case, maybe sort of.
我觉得我要通过添加一个特殊情况来修复这个 也许有点像
OK.
好的
And maybe I'll just return 0.
也许我只会返回 0
Seems reasonable.
听起来合理
So I made a change.
我做了一个改变
I could debug again.
我可以再次调试
I should do what?
我应该做什么
I should put it at the start.
我应该把它放在开头
Does it really matter?
这真的重要吗
OK.
好的
Well, if it doesn't matter, I'll leave it as I wrote it.
如果不重要的话 我就按照我写的方式留着它
So it's authentic.
这是真实的
It's live.
这是实况
OK.
好的
So I tried it again.
我再试了一次
So I got the test from failing to passing, which is nice.
我把测试从不及格变成及格了 这很不错
It's great.
太好了
But hold on.
但等等
There's only one.
只有一个
I have nine more to go.
我还有九个要做
So I'll run all the tests again.
我会再次运行所有的测试
And hopefully, by solving that one tricky one, I knocked out a bunch.
希望通过解决那个棘手的问题 我能解决一堆问题
So maybe you remember from earlier, I was passing 3 of 13 or something.
也许你还记得之前的情况 我通过了 13 个中的 3 个或者其他什么
Now I'm passing 5, which is good.
现在我通过了 5 个 这很好
I'm like, Genshin Impacting.
我就像在玩原神一样
I don't know what that is.
我不知道那是什么
OK.
好的
OK, great.
好的 太棒了
So I have more failures to go.
我还有更多失败要解决
So I still have to keep playing this game and make some of these x's go away.
我还得继续玩这个游戏 把一些 X 去掉
So which one do you want to tackle next?
那么接下来你想解决哪一个
And again, you've got to pick one that's, I like picking the easy ones.
再次强调 你得选一个 我喜欢选容易的
If you want to, you can go tackle this ridiculous one.
如果你愿意 你可以去解决这个荒谬的
But I'm not going to do that, because it seems hard.
但我不会这么做 因为这看起来很难
So what do you want to do next?
那么你想接下来做什么
Test negative.
测试为阴性
Yeah, let's do that.
是啊 我们就这么做吧
OK, which one is test negative?
哪一个是测试阴性
Oh, you don't want to test negative?
你不想测试阴性
OK.
好的
Well, that's actually not a bad idea, which is maybe before we even get variance working, maybe we should make sure average is good.
其实这不是一个坏主意 也许在我们甚至让变异工作之前 也许我们应该确保平均值是好的
Because remember, we wrote a lot of tests for our helper method average, and we know that variance relies on average.
因为记住 我们为我们的辅助方法average写了很多测试 而且我们知道方差依赖于平均值
That's a good idea.
这是个好主意
Maybe we should make our average test work first, because some of these averages are not coming out right.
也许我们应该先让我们的平均测试起作用 因为这些平均数有些不对
That's a good point.
这是个很好的观点
So which average one should we do?
那么我们应该做哪个平均值呢
Let's not do any of the ridiculously hard ones.
让我们不要做任何非常困难的
How many averages do we have?
我们有多少个平均数
We have this one is failing, this one is failing.
我们有这个出问题了 这个也是有问题的
Preference?
有偏好吗
No preference?
没有偏好
I'll do output, not integers, because I felt like it.
我会输出而不是整数 因为我觉得这样做比较好
And again, there's no right answer.
再次强调 没有正确答案
If you did the other one, things would still be OK.
如果你选择了另一个 情况也会还好
OK, so yet again, I find myself in the average function, or we find ourselves, because we're doing it together.
再次 我发现自己在平均函数里 或者说我们发现自己在里面 因为我们是一起做的
So at this point, I can start looking inside.
在这个点 我可以开始往里面看了
And remember, debugging is kind of the art of checking what actually happened and what you expected to happen.
记住 调试有点像是检查实际发生了什么和你期望发生了什么的艺术
So I stop right here.
我就停在这里
And based on my knowledge of averages and stuff,
根据我对平均数等知识的了解
I think sum should probably be the sum of all this stuff.
我认为总和应该是所有这些东西的总和
And I think nums.length should be however long this is.
我认为 nums.length 应该是这个东西有多长
So let's check if they match what I expect.
让我们检查它们是否与我的预期相匹配
I guess I could also check that this array matches the input.
我猜我也可以检查一下这个数组是否与输入匹配
I feel pretty confident that it does.
我觉得它很有可能是匹配的
Actually, do I feel confident?
其实 我是不是感觉自信
Maybe you're like trolling me.
也许你在逗我
OK.
好吧
It matches?
它匹配吗
OK.
好的
Thank you.
谢谢
OK.
好的
So I can check.
那我可以检查一下
Well, how many things here?
那么 这里有多少东西
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8.
1、2、3、4、5、6、7、8
Is that 8?
那就是8个吗
1, 2, 3, 4.
1、2、3、4
Counting up here is hard.
这里数起来有点难
What about the sum?
总和呢
5, 10, 15, 20, 25, 30, 35, 45, 55, 59.
5、10、15、20、25、30、35、45、55、59
OK.
好的
Interesting.
有趣
So what that tells me, and this is also a nice little debugging tip, is because I'm setting breakpoints, I can also separate out where did the bug happen.
告诉我的是 这也是一个很好的调试提示 因为我设置了断点 我也可以分开bug出现在哪里
Did it happen after what's happening the line right now or before the line right now?
它是在当前行之后发生还是之前发生的
So at first, I didn't say this out loud because I thought I was going to cleverly find it.
一开始 我没有大声说出来 因为我以为我会聪明地找到它
I thought you were going to screw up the for loop and be like, aha, there's a little off by one here or something.
我以为你会搞砸for循环 然后说 啊哈 这里有一个小问题
That was my first hypothesis.
这是我的第一个假设
But why am I able to rule out that hypothesis?
但是为什么我能够排除那个假设呢
Because initially, my guess was like, oh, you probably messed me up by making this for loop wrong.
因为最初 我的猜测是 你可能搞砸了 让这个for循环错了
You probably just made this a 1 or something.
你可能只是把这个设成了1什么的
I didn't know, but that's what I thought.
我不知道 但那是我当时的想法
The reason why I can rule that out is because I stopped right here, and at this point in the code, suns is correct, nums.length is correct, and this array is correct.
我能排除的原因是因为我就在这里停下来了 在代码的这一点上 suns是正确的 nums.length也是正确的 这个数组也是正确的
So everything at this point matches what I expect.
这一点上的一切都符合我的预期
So even if I have no idea what this for loop is doing, and I just can't even read this code, I feel pretty good that this is doing what I expect.
即使我不知道这个for循环在做什么 我甚至都读不懂这段代码 我还是觉得这符合我的期望
which is kind of nice.
这挺好的
So I'm pretty confident that the sum is correct.
我相当有信心总和是正确的
I'm pretty confident that nums.length is correct.
我相当有信心nums.length是正确的
So the error must happen either on this line or from something that set up this line.
错误肯定要么发生在这一行 要么是由设置这一行的某些东西引起的
So maybe I'll step over this line to see what happened.
也许我会跨过这条线看看发生了什么
That's one idea.
这是一个想法
Another idea is maybe if I don't want to step over this line, I could just write it in the box.
另一个想法是 如果我不想跨过这条线 我可以把它写在框里
So remember, this box lets you evaluate stuff.
记住 这个框让你评估东西
So I can evaluate, hey, what's the value of sum?
我可以评估 sum的值是多少
It's 59.
是59
What's the value of sum divided by nums.length?
sum除以nums.length的值是多少
It's 7.
这是7
So this function is going to return 7.
这个函数会返回7
That also matches the error message from earlier.
这也与之前的错误消息相匹配
What's the expected?
预期是什么
What is this supposed to be?
这应该是什么
It's not supposed to be 7.
它不应该是7
It's supposed to be 7.375.
应该是7.375
Aha.
啊哈
So writing this test was useful because it was 7, but it's actually 7.375.
写这个测试很有用 因为它是7 但实际上是7.375
So I look.
我看看
Hmm.
嗯
I feel like I see it.
我觉得我看到了
I don't know if anyone else sees it.
我不知道别人有没有看到
But I don't know how to illustrate it further besides just stopping here and realizing that it's 59, that the sum is correct and the nums and the length is correct, but the division output is wrong.
但是我不知道如何进一步说明 除了停在这里意识到它是59 总和是正确的 数字和长度也是正确的 但是除法输出是错误的
So I've narrowed it down, I feel like.
我已经缩小范围了 我觉得
Yeah, I think you have the same issue I do, which is that this is an integer.
是的 我觉得你和我有同样的问题 就是这是一个整数
And when I take an integer and I divide it by another integer, I get an integer.
当我拿一个整数除以另一个整数时 我得到一个整数
OK, so you and I have the same thought, which is good.
你和我有同样的想法 这很好
It means I'm not going crazy up here.
这意味着我在这里不会发疯
So there's a couple of thoughts.
有几个想法
One thought was I could just like, hey, Java, please pretend this is a double.
一个想法是我可以像 Java 假装这是一个双精度
I'm going to try maybe something like this.
我打算试试可能是这样的
What if I make this a double?
如果我把这个变成双倍呢
I feel like that's OK, too.
我觉得那样也挺好的
OK, so let's try that.
那我们试试这个
OK, so I'll stop.
那我就停下来了
Unexpected error.
意外错误
I did not expect this to happen.
我没料到会发生这种情况
OK, what does it want?
它想要什么
It says, required int, but provided double.
它说 需要整数 但提供的是双精度数
So this is a syntax error.
这是一个语法错误
It's not even letting me run the code.
它甚至不让我运行代码
And it seems to me like what's happening is, aha, the function wants an int, but I want it to return double.
看起来发生的情况是 哈 函数想要一个整数 但我想要它返回双精度数
More syntax error.
更多的语法错误
So I'm going to go down here.
我要往下走
This needs to be a double.
这应该是一个双精度
OK.
好的
I'm catching your bugs.
我在找你的错误
OK.
好的
Technically, they're my own bugs if we pretend this is me coding, but that's OK.
从技术上讲 如果我们假装这是我在编码 那么它们就是我的错误 但没关系
All right.
好的
So we'll run the tests again, see if anything changed.
我们会再次运行测试 看看有没有什么变化
I feel pretty good about the average now, but I still don't feel very good about the.
我对平均水平感觉还不错 但我对此仍感觉不太好
I don't feel.
我感觉不好
Thank you for whoever caught that, by the way.
顺便感谢一下谁发现了这个
Applause for whoever caught that.
为发现这个鼓掌
OK.
好的
We're making progress.
我们在取得进展
How much time do I have?
我还有多少时间
16 minutes.
16 分钟
OK.
好的
Yeah, I know I have to keep going.
是的 我知道我必须继续下去
OK, so now we're at, what, like seven past six failed?
现在我们是在 什么 六点零七过了
OK, so we still have more to do.
我们还有更多工作要做
I think they're all variance ones now.
我想它们现在都是方差项
OK, this is also why it's sometimes nice to write actual variable names, but whatever.
这也是为什么有时写实际的变量名会比较好 但无所谓
OK, or actual descriptive test names, but whatever.
或者实际的描述性测试名称 但随便
OK, what should we do next?
接下来我们应该做什么
Don't do big test.
不要进行大测试
Anything else?
还有其他事吗
Test variance?
测试变异
I think this one seems reasonable.
我觉得这个似乎是合理的
Test variance.
测试变异
测试差异
OK, so I can just check what it is.
我可以直接检查一下是什么
In case you forgot, test variance.
以防你忘了 测试差异
Where is test variance?
测试差异在哪里
There it is.
就在那里
So this is one of the ones that we had from the start.
这是我们一开始就有的其中之一
It's 1, 2, 3, 4.
它是1、2、3、4
We think the output should be 1.25.
我们认为输出应该是1.25
I agree.
我同意
Let's test this.
让我们测试一下
So let's go unset the average breakpoint, because we feel pretty good about average now.
那么让我们取消平均断点 因为我们对平均感觉很好
Why do we feel so good about average, even though we didn't have an autograder?
为什么我们对平均感到很满意 即使我们没有自动评分器呢
Because we wrote our own test and it worked.
因为我们编写了自己的测试 而且它有效
So let's do test variance.
让我们测试方差
And this time, it's a little bit trickier.
这次有点棘手
I have no clue.
我一点头绪也没有
I've not even looked at variance before.
我以前甚至都没看过方差
So I have no clue what's going to go wrong.
我不知道会出什么问题
So maybe I'll just set a breakpoint inside test variance itself.
也许我会在测试方差内部设置一个断点
And I'll just go through line by line until I find something.
然后我会逐行检查 直到找到问题所在
Maybe I'll find something.
也许我会找到一些线索
Maybe I won't.
也许我不会
Maybe I'll learn something.
也许我会学到点什么
So at this point, I'm at variance.variance.
在这一点上 我和你们不太一样
Remember your little debugging buttons?
记得你们的小调试按钮吗
I could step over.
我可以跨过去
But if I step over, I'm going to skip all of the variance function executing.
但如果我跨过去 我就会跳过所有的方差函数执行
So instead, I want to step into the variance function to see what's going on.
我想要进入方差函数里面看看到底发生了什么
So I find myself in the variance function.
我发现自己在方差函数里
Great.
太好了
What can I do now?
现在我能做什么
I could step into the average function to watch it run.
我可以进入平均函数里看看它是如何运行的
But I feel pretty good about the average function.
但我对平均函数感觉挺好的
So maybe I'll just be bold, and I'll step over, and I'll be like, average, I don't care what's happening inside of you.
也许我会大胆一些 我会跳过去 就像是 平均值 我不在乎里面发生了什么
I feel like I already spent enough time on the average, so I'll skip over you.
我觉得我已经在平均值上花了足够的时间 我会跳过你
And something nice is the debugger tells me a is equal to 2.5.
还有一件好事是调试器告诉我 a 等于 2.5
And I can even check right now.
而且我现在甚至可以检查一下
Does 2.5 match what I expect the average to be?
2.5 是否符合我期望的平均值
I don't know.
我不知道
Let me use my handy-dandy built-in calculator.
让我使用我的方便易用的内置计算器
OK.
好的
I want this divided by 4.
我想要这个除以 4
OK, it's 2.5.
是2.5
Thank you, Java.
谢谢 Java
So I feel pretty good about A, whatever this is.
我对 a 感觉还不错 不管这是什么
I think that's the right number.
我觉得那是正确的数字
OK, let's keep going.
继续吧
The next line is this.
下一行是这样的
I step over, and I get this new array.
我跨过去 然后我得到这个新数组
And again, the debugger shows it to me.
再次 调试器把它显示给我看
It's got an array.
它有一个数组
It's got nums.length, which I guess is four elements.
它有nums.length 我猜是四个元素
There they are.
它们在那里
They're all zeros.
它们全都是零
OK, good.
很好
Let's keep going.
我们继续
Here's a loop.
这是一个循环
So maybe I'll step into the loop.
也许我会进入这个循环
So double difference equals num sub i plus a. There's the difference.
双重差异等于 num 减 i 加 a 这就是差异
So where's the difference?
那么差异在哪里
It's 3.5.
是3.5
I feel like this difference is not what I expected.
我觉得这个差异不是我预期的
Does anyone else feel the same?
有其他人有同样的感觉吗
I could be totally wrong, by the way.
我可能完全错了 顺便说一下
So I'm kind of relying on you to tell me.
我有点依赖你告诉我
Does anyone on Zoom?
在Zoom上有人吗
Someone said, why are we adding?
有人说 我们为什么要添加
That's my question.
这是我的问题
Why are we adding?
我们为什么要添加
What does Zoom think?
Zoom认为怎么样
Are we adding?
我们在加吗
I don't know.
我不知道
They're still on the return type?
他们还在讨论返回类型吗
Oh, OK.
好的
It's like time zone difference.
就像时区差异一样
OK.
好的
Tape delay.
录音延迟
OK.
好的
I feel like this should not be add, because you called it difference.
我觉得这不该加上 因为你说这是差异
I feel like this should be, do people agree with me?
我觉得应该这样 大家同意吗
I don't know.
我不确定
Yes?
是吗
OK, we'll make it subtract.
我们就把它减掉
If I'm wrong, I blame you.
如果我错了 那就怪你
OK, so let's make it subtract.
那我们就让它减去
If I'm feeling bold, I could just run the test to see what happens.
如果我感觉大胆一点 我可以直接运行测试看看会发生什么
Maybe the output will change.
也许输出会改变
I could also set the debugger again.
我也可以再次设置调试器
Maybe I'll do that.
也许我会这么做
OK, so let's go back.
那我们就回去
Let's debug.
让我们调试
Having fun yet?
玩得开心吗
OK, so I'll step in.
那我来了
I step in.
我来了
OK, so with the plus and minus, they're fixed.
加号和减号是固定的
We should now have these numbers, each subtracted, or 2.5 should be subtracted from each of these numbers.
现在我们应该有这些数字 每个数字都减去 或者应该从每个数字中减去2.5
Is that right?
对吗
I feel like it is.
我感觉就是这样
Where's my spec?
我的规格在哪
Sometimes when in doubt, by the way, read the spec, because you might miss stuff.
有时候当你犹豫不决的时候 顺便读一下规格 因为你可能会错过一些东西
So yeah, it seems like we want to take all the numbers 1, 2, 3, 4, subtract 2.5.
看起来我们想要取出所有的数字 1、2、3、4 然后减去 2.5
This spec helpfully tells me that I should expect to see 2.25, 0.25, 0.25, 2.25.
这个规格很贴心地告诉我 我应该期望看到 2.25、0.25、0.25、2.25
So I can even write down those numbers and be like, aha, those are the numbers that I want to pop out of this difference variable.
我甚至可以把这些数字写下来 然后说 啊哈 这些就是我想要从这个差值变量中弹出的数字
So actually, let me just check that.
实际上 让我来检查一下
So maybe what I'll do is I'll set a breakpoint here.
也许我会在这里设置一个断点
And then I'll step over the breakpoint, and I'll see, what was the value of difference?
然后我会跳过断点 看看 差值是多少
It was negative 1.5.
是负1.5
OK, that's what I want, right?
这就是我想要的 对吧
It's negative 1.5.
是负1.5
That's the difference because I haven't squared it yet.
那就是因为我还没有对它进行平方运算
And what if I want to come back to this breakpoint?
如果我想回到这个断点怎么办
I could just mash the Step button until I get back.
我可以一直按着“步骤”按钮 直到我回到原点
Or I can use my magic little continue button to keep running this program until it gets back to the same breakpoint.
或者我可以使用我的神奇小“继续”按钮 让这个程序一直运行 直到它回到相同的断点
This time, when I'm back at this breakpoint, i is equal to 1.
这次 当我回到这个断点时 i 等于 1
It's the next for loop iteration.
这是下一个 for 循环的迭代
Num sub i is now 2, because it's the next number down.
Num 减去 i 现在是 2 因为它是下一个减少的数字
a, I hope, is still 2.5.
a 希望 仍然是 2.5
It is.
它就是
So if I step over, the difference is negative 0.5.
如果我跨过去 差异就是负0.5
There it is.
就是这样
I can do it again.
我可以再做一遍
I step over, difference is 0.5.
我跨过去 差异是0.5
There it is.
就是这样
And the last one, I think, was 1.5.
我想最后一个是1.5
OK, great.
好的 太棒了
So I feel pretty good about this double difference.
我对这个双重差异感觉相当不错
Whatever the heck it's doing, it seems to be getting these four numbers out.
不管它在做什么 似乎都能得到这四个数字
So again, I'm sort of like, if you build a timeline, like a movie of what's going on, I feel like if I'm watching the movie, everything is good up until line 19, and I still have to check these lines that come after.
再说一遍 我有点像 如果你建立一个时间线 就像是正在发生的电影 我觉得如果我在看这部电影 一切都很好直到第19行 然后我还得检查这些之后的行
So I'm feeling pretty good.
我感觉不错
OK.
好的
So what comes next?
那么接下来是什么
Well, now it seems like I'm trying to fill in the squared differences.
现在看起来我正在尝试填充这些平方差异
OK, so I'm not going to lie.
我不会撒谎
I expected a specific bug that you would enter into this function and is not there.
我预料到一个特定的错误 你会输入到这个函数里 但它不存在
And now I feel betrayed.
现在我感到受伤了
OK, so that's fine.
那没关系
So you did this on purpose.
这是你故意的
OK, that's fine.
没关系
So I was expecting a specific bug here, and I was going to be like, oh, I'm so smart.
我在这里预料到一个特定的错误 然后我会说 我真聪明
I caught it.
我抓到了
But it's not there.
但它不在那里
OK, so I guess I have to try.
我想我得试试
So what should I do?
那我应该怎么办呢
I feel like I feel pretty good about the differences.
我觉得我对这些差异感觉很好
So maybe I'll start over.
也许我会重新开始
Maybe I'll start debugging at difference again.
也许我会再次从差异处开始调试
OK.
好的
Maybe the whole thing works, and I just don't know.
也许整个东西都能运行 只是我不知道
Maybe I should just run the test to be sure.
也许我应该运行一下测试来确保
I have 10 minutes.
我有10分钟
OK.
好的
Maybe I'll just run the tests.
也许我只是跑一下测试
Ah, they don't all work.
啊 它们并不都起作用
OK.
好的
But we got close.
但我们已经接近了
And unfortunately, only the big test is wrong, the one I really didn't want to write.
而且不幸的是 只有大测试出错了 这是我真的不想写的那个
OK.
好的
I was expecting the difference thing to not work.
我预料到差异的事情不会起作用
Seems like it did.
看起来好像是的
But if it didn't work, what I would do is I would set a breakpoint here, and I would check that this is filling in the right values.
但如果它没有起作用 我会在这里设置一个断点 然后检查这是否填充了正确的值
Luckily, I didn't have to.
幸运的是 我不必这样做
But now I have 10 minutes to tackle this one.
但现在我有10分钟来处理这个问题
I feel like this one's going to be annoying.
我觉得这个问题会很烦人
OK, let's do it.
让我们开始吧
That's fine.
那没问题
Sometimes that happens, right?
有时候会发生这种情况 对吧
Sometimes the test you write is just annoying, and it's hard to find.
有时候你写的测试就是很烦人 很难找到问题所在
It could also, sometimes if you don't want to debug this, we could write more tests that are not this one to try to get it to fail on one that's not as annoyingly large as this one.
有时候也可以 如果你不想调试这个的话 我们可以写更多不是这个的测试来尝试让它在一个不那么让人讨厌大的测试上失败
That's also a possibility.
那也是一种可能性
Don't tell me the test itself is wrong.
别告诉我测试本身有问题
I feel like it might be, but it might not be.
我觉得可能有 但也可能没有
OK, what should I do?
我该怎么办
Does anyone have ideas?
有人有想法吗
Help me out.
帮帮我
You're leaving me out to dry alone.
你丢下我一个人晾在这儿了
So I guess, because I don't know what's going on, maybe I'll just set the breakpoint here, and I'll go through.
我猜 因为我不知道发生了什么 也许我就在这里设置断点 然后逐步执行
And if anyone has inspiration, please tell me, because I actually don't have any at this point.
如果有人有灵感 请告诉我 因为我实际上现在一点都没有
I have 10 minutes left.
我还有10分钟
OK.
好的
And if I don't get it, I'm going to have to ask you for the answer in shame, and I don't want to do that.
如果我搞不定 我就只能丢脸地向你请教答案了 我可不想这样
OK, so what should I do?
那我应该怎么办
OK, input size is 1,000.
输入大小是1,000
I feel pretty good about that.
我对此感觉很好
I have this array of 1,000, which I feel pretty good about.
我有这个大小为1,000的数组 我对此感觉很好
This i equals 1 is really messing me up, though.
这个i等于1真的让我感到困扰 不过
I don't like this i equals 1.
我不喜欢这个i等于1
Let's see.
让我们看看
But you want the first 1,000 cubes.
但是你想要前1,000个立方数
So I know that the first three numbers should be 1, 8, and 27.
我知道前三个数字应该是1、8和27
You told me this was fine before lecture, but I don't trust you.
你在讲座前告诉过我这没问题 但我不相信你
So I'm going to check.
我要检查一下
OK.
好的
So input is 2.
输入是2
Wait a minute.
等一下
You told me this was fine.
你告诉过我这没问题
What the heck?
到底是什么鬼
OK.
好的
So this should be 1.
这应该是1
But it's 2 here.
但这里是2
So I found the difference between what was expected and what actually happened.
我发现了预期和实际发生之间的差异
Aha.
啊哈
I know your tricks now.
我现在知道你的诀窍了
Here, I was told that this test was probably doing something with the first 1,000 cubes, which were 1,827.
在这里 我被告知这个测试可能是在处理前 1,000 个立方体 它们是 1,827
Here, I can see that they are not, because this number is 2.
在这里 我可以看到它们不是 因为这个数字是 2
And I bet if I keep going, they're going to be more.
我敢打赌 如果我继续下去 它们会更多
OK, that's not right, because that should be 8.
那不对 因为那应该是 8
Hm.
嗯
OK, that's not right.
那不对
That's 0.
那是0
That's 7.
那是7
OK, so none of these are right.
这些都不对
These are not the cubes of the numbers.
这些不是数字的立方
OK, so I don't feel good about this.
我对这个不感觉好
OK, so something about the test is wrong.
测试有问题
And unfortunately, that's something that happens sometimes.
不幸的是 这有时会发生
Sometimes your function is good, but the test itself is wrong.
有时候你的函数是好的 但测试本身是错误的
And sometimes we just have to deal with that.
有时候我们只是不得不处理这个
And it's kind of annoying.
而且这有点烦人
But at least we've narrowed it down a little bit.
但至少我们已经缩小了范围一点点
So could the error be on this line?
那么错误可能就在这一行吗
Oops.
哎呀
Could the error be on this assert line?
错误可能在这个断言行吗
It could.
可能吧
But I feel like if I'm watching the movie play, I feel like something has already gone wrong here.
但我觉得如果我在看电影的话 我觉得这里已经出了点问题
And because something has already gone wrong here, I don't really care whether this is right or not.
而且因为这里已经出了点问题 我其实并不在乎这是否正确
It could be wrong.
可能是错的
I'll check it later.
稍后我会检查一下
But I've already figured out that something is wrong around this loop.
但我已经弄清楚这个循环周围出了点问题
So I should probably start checking around here.
我应该从这里开始检查
OK, so what should I do?
那我应该怎么做呢
I still don't feel comfortable about this i equals 1, and then this being i minus 1, and this being i. That feels kind of weird to me.
我还是对这个 i 等于 1 然后这个是 i 减 1 这个是 i 的感觉有点奇怪
So maybe I'll check that.
也许我会检查一下
Is there anything else that people noticed?
还有别人注意到的吗
I don't know.
我不知道
Let's keep checking.
我们继续检查吧
Because the numbers are still totally off, too.
因为数字还是完全不对
It's not like they're cube numbers, and they're just kind of off.
这不像是立方数一样 有点奇怪
OK, so I step into here.
我走进这里
You want me to use times?
你想让我使用乘号吗
OK, well, hold on.
等等
So that's not a bad idea.
这不是一个坏主意
Maybe you use times.
也许你使用乘号
I'm going to check one thing, just because I'm not sure.
我要检查一件事 只是因为我不确定
So this input is 0.
这个输入是0
And then in 0, I'm putting i, which is 1.
然后在0里 我放的是i 也就是1
So I feel pretty good about that.
我对此感觉相当不错
And how do I know?
我怎么知道呢
Because i is 1.
因为i是1
I'm putting something in input 0.
我在输入0里放了一些东西
The next time around, i is equal to 2.
下一次循环 i等于2
I'm putting something in input 1.
我在输入1中放了点东西
So I feel pretty good about the indexing, although it looked kind of strange at first.
我对索引感觉还不错 虽然一开始看起来有点奇怪
Someone said something about pow or something?
有人说了什么关于 pow 或者什么的
Tell me.
告诉我
Let's Google it.
我们来谷歌一下
You want me to Google it?
你要我帮你谷歌吗
OK, I'll Google.
我来谷歌
I've done so much Googling today.
我今天谷歌了很多
But Google is your friend, though.
但谷歌是你的朋友啊
As long as you set your sources, it's totally OK.
只要你设定好你的来源 完全没问题
What should I Google?
我应该谷歌什么
OK.
好的
Like this?
像这样
Operators in Java.
Java中的运算符
I disabled my ad blocker.
我禁用了我的广告拦截器
I disabled, OK, hold on.
我禁用了 等等
Where is it?
它在哪里
I don't want to support you.
我不想支持你
OK, so this thing.
这个东西
I don't know what any of this stuff means.
我不知道这些东西的任何含义
I don't know what this is.
我不知道这是什么
But it's definitely not power.
但这绝对不是力量
I don't know about you.
我不知道你呢
I don't feel like this is, this is power?
我觉得这不是 这就是力量吗
This is not power.
这不是力量
OK.
好的
All right, so what do I do next?
那么接下来我该怎么办呢
How to power, OK.
如何给电源 好的
I don't know.
我不知道
OK.
好的
Math.pow.
Math.pow
Thank you, Google.
谢谢 Google
OK.
好的
I can even cite if I wanted to.
如果我想的话 我甚至可以引用
Does Java have an exponentiation?
Java有指数运算吗
No, no, no.
不 不 不
OK.
好的
Math.pow.
Math.pow
OK.
好的
So I used u. So where's my source?
我用了u 那么我的源代码在哪里
OK.
好的
I used this.
我用了这个
Great, I cited it.
太好了 我引用了它
I have five minutes to fix this.
我有五分钟来解决这个问题
What did I use?
我用了什么
Math.pow.
Math.pow
I actually don't know what the argument order is.
实际上我不知道参数的顺序是什么
I'm guessing this is the base and this is the exponent, so it's 2 to the 3.
我猜这是底数 这是指数 是2的3次方
This is 3 to the 2.
这是3的2次方
So I want i to the 3.
我想要i变成3
So I want math.pow i cubed.
我想要用math.pow把i立方
I feel pretty good about that.
我对此感觉挺好的
OK.
好的
The import is there.
导入已经存在
I guess there was no import needed.
我猜可能不需要导入
OK, I feel better about that.
我对此感觉更好了
I'll use the debugger to double check.
我会使用调试器再次检查一遍
Let's hope.
希望如此
OK, if this is wrong, I'm going to have to beg your forgiveness.
如果错了 我只能祈求你的原谅了
OK, so this time, I'm expecting number one to show up here.
这次 我期待着第一个数字出现在这里
So I step over.
我单步执行
That's one.
这是第一个
Feeling pretty good.
感觉不错
This time, I'm calling math.pow on i is equal to 2, 2 cubed.
这次 我调用 math.pow 在 i 等于 2 的时候是等于 2 的立方
That better be 8.
那应该是 8
OK, so is that right?
那么是对的吗
Coming up here, I don't even know my cube numbers anymore.
过来这里 我甚至都不知道我的立方数了
So it's 8.
是 8
The next one is 27.
下一个是 27
The next one is 64.
下一个是 64
So I feel pretty good about this.
我对这感觉挺好的
I have no idea if this number is correct.
我不知道这个数字是否正确
I'll have to take your word that this number is correct.
我只能相信这个数字是正确的
It's right there, 8.06 times 10 to the 16.
就在那里 8.06乘以10的16次方
OK.
好的
So with four minutes left, if there's another bug after this, I am so screwed.
剩下四分钟 如果这之后还有另一个 bug 那我真的完蛋了
You don't even know.
你甚至都不知道
OK.
好的
I mean, you're not screwed, because you have extra time.
我的意思是 你没问题 因为你有额外的时间
You're not doing this on like a one-hour clock.
你不是在像一个一小时的时钟上做这个
Well, yeah, you've got to be paranoid when you're debugging.
是的 当你在调试时 你必须要很谨慎
OK.
好的
So I'll not get some.
我就不会得到一些东西
OK.
好的
Everybody cross the fingers.
大家都交叉手指
Don't breathe.
别呼吸
All this works.
这一切都有效
OK.
好的
Thank you, everybody.
谢谢大家
Thank you for catching that.
谢谢你注意到了这一点
OK.
好的
But wait, that was only one of the tests.
等等 那只是其中一个测试
I should check the other ones too.
我应该也检查一下其他的
If all of these other ones work, you can go home three minutes early, so everybody pray.
如果所有这些其他的都正常 你们可以提前三分钟回家 大家祈祷吧
OK, go home.
好的 回家吧
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
等等 等等 等等
I'm sorry.
抱歉
I have one more slide, so maybe don't go just yet.
我还有一张幻灯片 可能还不要走
Final, final slide, really quickly, if you're curious, they're at the end.
最后一张 真的很快 如果你好奇的话 它们在最后面
I shouldn't have been so hasty.
我不应该那么仓促
But there's also an extra video if you're curious.
但如果你好奇的话 还有一个额外的视频
Basically, what we do not recommend, do not spam the autograder to check if your code is correct.
基本上 我们不建议 不要刷屏自动评分器来检查你的代码是否正确
The autograder is limited.
自动评分器有限
It will not let you spam the autograder.
它不会让你垃圾邮件自动评分器
So we don't recommend doing this.
我们不建议这样做
It's slow.
速度慢
It doesn't work.
它不工作
It doesn't let you figure out what's going on.
它不让你弄清楚发生了什么
Oops.
哎呀
So try doing what we just did, which is write the test ahead of time, invest time early.
尝试做我们刚刚做的事情 即提前编写测试 及早投入时间
We'll save you time in the long run.
我们会为你省下很多时间的
Oh, I shouldn't have let people go at the end.
我不应该让人们在最后离开的
OK.
好的
Well, we figured it out.
我们搞清楚了
So those are the videos.
这些就是视频
OK.
好的
Another.
再来一次
OK.
好的
No more.
不再了
We're never doing this again.
我们再也不会这样做了
OK.
好的